Guide to the Samuel Thompson's Nephew & Co. Records 1875-1940 MS 624
New-York Historical Society
Samuel Thompson's Nephew & Co. collection
1875-1940
New-York Historical Society
Samuel Thompson's Nephew & Co.
MS 624
200 Linear feet in 46 records cartons, 121 letter boxes, 86 volumes
TBD
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Samuel Thompson's Nephew & Co. was a shipping and mercantile business in New York City. Established by Samuel Thompson (1795-1855) in 1825, the business carried his name for 20 years. It was then changed to Samuel Thompson & Nephew, which later became Samuel Thompson's Nephew & Co. in 1870. A partner in the company was John W. Mason (1820-1903) who also established a wire rope and cordage business in association with Samuel Thompson & Nephew in 1866. The firm functioned as agents for numerous vessels and was involved in the immigrant trade in 1840's and 1850's. It also managed affairs for the Black Star line of Liverpool packets. Samuel Thompson was also related to Jeremiah Thompson (1782-1855) who was instrumental in the creation of the famous Black Ball line in 1817.
(The above note was taken from the finding aid for the Samuel Thompson's Nephew & Co. Collection held by Mystic Seaport.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
TBD
Related Materials
Another collection of Samuel Thompson's Nephew & Co. records, and predecessor firms, is held by Mystic Seaport.
Scope and Contents
TBD
Shipping; Merchants.; Merchant companies -- New York (N.Y.).; Financial records.
- Invoices, checks, bills of lading, vouchers, purchase and shipping orders, telegrams, 1900-1933 (Box 122)
- Account books, bills of lading, checks, order forms, telegrams, 1906-1936 (Box 123)
- Bills, duties, account books, tax assessments, shipping tickets, 1906-1917 (Box 124)
- Order forms, invoices, bills of lading, sale contracts, 1912-1913, 1928 (Box 125)
- Paid vouchers, invoices, receipts, clippings, bills of lading, account books, real estate tax bills, 1889-1937 (Box 126)
- Checks, insurance policies, deposit slips, bills, vouchers, bills of lading, tax clippings, account books, 1900-1927 (Box 127)
- Checks, vouchers, freight bills, invoices, insurance policies, companies' promotional materials, 1905-1931 (Box 128)
- Alphabetized order forms, receipts, 1911 (Box 129)
- Checks, bills of lading, receipts, order forms, telegrams, elevator inspection reports, shipping tickets, 1910-1932 (Box 130)
- Checks, orders, insurance policies, stock offerings, bills of lading, 1906-1933 (Box 131)
- Checks, telegraph codes, court documents, vouchers, order forms, bills of lading, 1894-1937 (Box 132)
- Bills of lading, order forms, 1922-1927 (Box 133)
- Shipping tickets, order forms, telegrams, 1904-1936 (Box 134)
- Checks, telegrams, bills of lading, orders, copies of bills, 1911-1933 (Box 135)
- Checks, insurance policies, account books, telegrams, orders, shipping tickets, 1902-1933 (Box 136)
- Checks, orders, insurance policies, correspondence, invoices, 1923-1936 (Box 137)
- Account books, annual reports, paid vouchers, court papers, orders, clippings, 1894-1923 (Box 138)
- Bills of lading, account books, orders, shipment receipts, invoices, 1908-1933 (Box 139)
- Orders, account books, invoices, 1899-1926 (Box 140)
- Insurance policies, checks, bills of lading, purchase orders, 1908-1927 (Box 141)
- Checks, bills of lading, insurance policies, 1896-1937 (Box 142)
- Checks, bills of lading, insurance policies, 1875-1932 (Box 143)
- Checks, receipts, 1884-1923 (Box 144)
- Account books, bills of lading, orders, shipping forms, published materials, 1908-1929 (Box 145)
- Invoices, purchase orders, bills, 1937-1940 (Box 146)
- Shipping tickets, 1920 (Box 147)
- Local laws, bills of lading, delivery forms, 1923-1936 (Box 148)
- Shipping tickets, 1918-1919 (Box 149)
- Shipping tickets, 1918 (Box 150)
- Financial papers: bills, receipts, checks, circa 1900-1915 (Box 151)
- Checks, bills, insurance policies, circa 1911-1921 (Box 152)
- Financial papers: guarantees, insurances, checks, bills, circa 1915-1920 (Box 153)
- Bills, checks receipts, circa 1903-1905 (Box 154)
- Financial papers: NYC bills, insurance, checks, correspondence, circa 1892-1911 (Box 155)
- Misc. financial papers, circa 1892-1910 (Box 156)
- Balance books, insurance, deposit slips, circa 1895-1915 (Box 157)
- Financial papers: insurance, lots, receipts, vouchers, checks, circa 1896-1919 (Box 158)
- Financial papers, circa 1910 (Box 149)
- Papers, circa 1910 (Box 160)
- Misc. business papers, circa 1905 (Box 161)
- Papers and correspondence, circa 1900 (Box 162)
- Misc. papers, circa 1900 (Box 163)
- Papers, circa 1900 (Box 164)
- Business papers, circa 1900 (Box 165)
- Financial papers and correspondence, circa 1900 (Box 166)
- Bills, checks, correspondence, circa 1900 (Box 167)